You learned the basics of hidden Markov models in an earlier lesson.
在之前的课程里 你学习了隐马尔可夫模型 (HMM) 的基础知识
To recap, HMMs are useful for detecting patterns through time.
重温一下 HMM 擅于检测与时间有关的模式
This is exactly what we are trying to do with an acoustic model.
而这正是我们想对声学模型进行的操作
HMMs can solve the challenge,
HMM 能解决
we identified earlier, of time variability.
我们之前提出的挑战 即时间差异性
For instance, my earlier example of speech versus speech,
比如 我之前举的例子 speech 的两种读法
the same word but spoken at different speeds.
虽然单词一样 但语速不同
We could train an HMM with label time series sequences to
我们可以用有标签的时序序列来训练 HMM
create individual HMM models for each particular sound unit.
为各特定声音单元创建 HMM 模型
The units could be phonemes,
这些单元可以是音位、
syllables, words, or even groups of words.
音节、单词 甚至是词组
Training and recognition are fairly straightforward,
训练和识别其实很简单
if our training and test data are isolated units.
只要我们用分离好的单元做训练和测试数据即可
We have many examples,
收集大量例子
we train them, we get a model for each word.
进行训练 为每个单词生成模型
Then recognition of a single word comes
这样一来 单词识别
down to scoring the new observation likelihood over each model.
其实就是比较每个模型的新观测概率值
It gets more complicated when our training data consists of
但如果训练数据包含连续的短语或句子 也即表述
continuous phrases or sentences which we'll refer to as utterances.
那过程就复杂许多了
How can the series of phonemes or words be separated in training?
训练时 我们要怎么分离一系列的音位或单词呢？
In this example, we have the word brick,
比如这里 单词 brick
connected continuously in nine different utterance combinations.
与其它九种表述无间断地连在一起
To train from continuous utterances HMMs can be tied together as pairs.
要用连续表述来训练 我们可以把 HMM 一对对地组合起来
We define these connectors as HMMs.
把这些连接符也定义成 HMM
In this case, we would train her brick,
具体说来 我们可以训练 her brick (她的砖)、
my brick, a brick,
my brick (我的砖)、a brick (一块砖)、
brick house, brick walkway,
brick house (砖房)、brick walkway (砖道)、
and brick wall, by tying the connecting states together.
和 brick wall (砖墙) 也就是让相连的状态组成一对
This will increase dimensionality.
这会增加维数
Not only will we need an HMM for each word,
不仅需要给每个单词建立 HMM
we need one for each possible work connection,
还要给每条可能的工作连接建立 HMM
which could be a lot if there are a lot of words.
如果单词很多 那需要的 HMM 就多了
The same principle applies if we use phonemes.
同样的原则也适用于音位
But for large vocabularies,
但如果词汇量很大
the dimensionality increase isn't as profound as with words.
用音位 维数增长就不会像用单词那么夸张
With a set of 40 phonemes,
如果一组有 40 个音位
we need 1600 HMMs to account for the transitions.
我们就需要 1600 个 HMM 来进行转换
Still a manageable number.
这个数字仍在可控范围
Once trained, the HMM models can be used to score
训练好后 我们就可以用 HMM 模型
new utterances through chains of probable paths.
给各可能路径链所产生的新表述评分 也即求得相应的概率